<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shubham Sachan</title><link>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Shubham Sachan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 10:38:16 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://shubhamsachan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PE - Disk performance</title><link>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/blogs/fio-test/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 10:38:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/blogs/fio-test/</guid><description>PE - Disk performance As a performance engineer, disk performance is a crucial factor while analysing the performance of any application. fio is a powerful utility to analyse disk performance. Check the following to understand more about the fio and why we should use it before making any conclusion for the disk or application performance. Link</description></item><item><title>Who is faster: Asyncio/MultiThreading/MultiProcessing/Sync in Python</title><link>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/blogs/who-is-faster/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 17:52:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/blogs/who-is-faster/</guid><description>As a curious performance engineer we always want to find out the fastest method and implement/advise the same to get the maximum performance.
In python we can see multiple ways of running the same piece of code depends on how it is being written and which of the following ( Asyncio / MultiThreading / MultiProcessing / Sync ) is being used.
As an experiment i have written a very small IO bound code and have implemented Asyncio / MultiThreading / MultiProcessing / Sync one by another see the performance.</description></item><item><title>Perfmon-aws-ec2: Missing Perf Counters/Metrics</title><link>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/blogs/perfmon-ec2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 17:52:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/blogs/perfmon-ec2/</guid><description>How-to-resolve-missing-Perf-Counters-Metrics-from-PerfMon-in-EC2-Windows-AWS While working on aws windows ec2 instance, i have observed that, sometimes, not all the perfmon perf Counters/metrics are available, and error appear when perfmon starts as in below image. click to see more</description></item><item><title/><link>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/404/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/404/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://shubhamsachan.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am a decade old performance engineer (software professional), part time blogger and a firm believer of ‘Karma’. And always go with the famous proverb:
“Nothing Happens By Chance, By Fate. You Create Your Own Fate By Your Actions. That’s Karma” During all these times in my professional experience I learned alot and have gone through many problems and challenges. And I believe neither am I the only who goes though this nor these problems or challenges are very unique.</description></item></channel></rss>